Knights of Labor Miscellaneous Publications on Microfilm 5466 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Knights of Labor Miscellaneous Publications on Microfilm
1885-1900
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Knights of Labor
5466 mf
0.11 cubic feet
1 microfilm reel
Publications (documents), microfilm.
This collection consists of publications of the Knights of Labor. Included are addresses, articles, journals, and the organization's Ritual.
5623362
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, September 26, 2012
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 13, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The Knights of Labor (K of L), officially Noble and Holy Order of the Knights of Labor, was the largest and one of the most important American labor organizations of the 1880s.
The Knights promoted the social and cultural uplift of the workingman, rejected Socialism and radicalism, demanded the eight-hour day, and promoted the producers ethic of republicanism.
It was never well organized, and after a rapid expansion in the mid-1880s, it suddenly lost its new members and became a small operation again. It was started in 1869, reached 28,000 members in 1880, by 1885 there were 100,000 members. Nearly 800,000 members had joined by 1886, however its poor organizational structure could not cope and it quickly became a failure. Most members left the movement in 1886-1887, leaving not many more than 100,000 but 1890. The remainder of the Knights of Labor continued until 1949, when the last 50 members dropped their affiliation.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of publications by the Knights of Labor.
Address of the Congress of the Knights...', Address of the General Manager...', Adelphon Kruptos', Building Laborers Int'l. Union of America', Coffeyville Dynamite Outrage', District Assembly Forty-Nine...', Official Journal of the NY Protective Assoc..', 'Ritual', and 'Santuary of Dist. Assembly 126...'
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5427 mf: Knights of Labor Constitutions on Microfilm 5503 mf a & b: Knights of Labor Papers on Microfilm 5890: Knights of Labor vs. Troy (NY) Stove Works Scrapbook
Knights of Labor.
5623362
- Address of the Congress of the Knights of Labor of the State of New York to the Sovereign Electors., 1896; 1 (Reel 1)
  Scope and Contents
  10 pp.
- Address of the General Master Workman, 1885; 2 (Reel 1)
  October 5, 1885. 21 pp.
- Adelphon Kruptos. The Full, Illustrated Ritual Including the 'Unwritten Work' and a Historical Sketch of the Order., 1886; 3 (Reel 1)
  Chicago: Ezra A. Cook. 56 pp.
- Building Laborers International Union of America., 1890; 4 (Reel 1)
  2 pp.
- The Coffeyville Dynamite Outrage, October l8th, 1888., 1889; 5 (Reel 1)
  Winfield, Kansas: American Nonconformist. 101 pp.
- District Assembly Forty-Nine, Knights of Labor. New York and Vicinity., 1888; 6 (Reel 1)
  New York: Concord Co-operative Printing Company. 32 pp.
- Official Journal of the New York Protective Associations Affiliated with District Assembly 49, 1899; 7 (Reel 1)
  32 pp.
- Official Journal of the Nev York Protective Associations Affiliated with District Assembly 49, 1900; 8 (Reel 1)
  34 pp.
- Ritual., 9 (Reel 1)
  23 pp.
- Sanctuary of District Assembly 126, K. of L. Issued by Order of the District Assembly. Why the General Officers Should be Deposed., 10 (Reel 1)
  No date. 4 pp.